<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Computer Application Training &#8211; BM College</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/computingit/computerapptraining/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Technology College of London</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 23:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Office Administrator with Technology Program (OAT)</title>
		<link>/office-administrator-with-technology-program-oat-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 07:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7758</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Computing and Academic Studies Office Administrator with Technology Program (OAT) &#160; Upgrade your office technology skills and follow through with your career goals The Office Administrator with Technology is a hands-on program designed to provide you with the computer and business skills required by administrative positions today. It is ideal for individuals who [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="schoolname">School of Computing and Academic Studies</h3>
<h3><em>Office Administrator with Technology Program (OAT)</em></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h4 id="tagline">Upgrade your office technology skills and follow through with your career goals</h4>
<div>
<h4></h4>
<p>The Office Administrator with Technology is a hands-on program designed to provide you with the computer and business skills required by administrative positions today. It is ideal for individuals who do not have previous education or background in computing as well as those who need to retrain or upgrade their present computer skills.</p>
<p>Upon completion of the program, you will be able to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use Microsoft Word to create professional documents</li>
<li>Create budgets and analyze data with Microsoft Excel</li>
<li>Design and deliver a presentation with Microsoft PowerPoint</li>
<li>Use Microsoft Outlook to manage schedules, contacts, and email</li>
<li>Design and develop a small database with Microsoft Access</li>
<li>Complete basic bookkeeping tasks with Simply Accounting</li>
<li>Prepare and understand financial reports</li>
<li>Use HTML, WordPress and Adobe Dreamweaver to build and manage a website</li>
<li>Enhance photos and create graphics with Adobe Photoshop Elements</li>
<li>Prepare marketing materials with Microsoft Publisher</li>
<li>Create diagrams and layouts with Microsoft Visio</li>
</ul>
<p>In addition, you will challenge two Microsoft Office Specialist exams and earn two valued industry certifications:</p>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft Word 2013</li>
<li>Microsoft Excel 2013</li>
</ul>
<p>The program consists of three months of classroom instruction, Monday to Friday, from 9:00 until 4:00, followed by a two-month full-time work term. It combines technical and professional courses with hands-on learning. Formal classroom instruction is complemented by realistic business projects.</p>
<p>There will be no extended breaks except for statutory holidays.</p>
<p>Classes are held at the BM College Downtown Campus.</p>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">Office Administrator with Technology</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>BM College Credential:</strong></td>
<td>Industry Partnership Certificate</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Location:</strong></td>
<td>Downtown London</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Length:</strong></td>
<td>5 months, Full-time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Start / End:</strong></td>
<td>April 1 &#8211; August 22, 2014</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total Tuition/Cost:</strong></td>
<td>Learn about Tuition &amp; Fees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Entry Requirements:</strong></td>
<td>View Requirements</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Graphic Communications Technology</title>
		<link>/graphic-communications-technology-2/</link>
		<comments>/graphic-communications-technology-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 07:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7754</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Business Graphic Communications Technology &#160; The world of printed communications is expanding and evolving at a rapid pace. Traditional print products are supplemented by digital delivery and technology advances in high-tech digital imaging. Graphic communications companies need highly skilled individuals and BM College graduates are driving print media into the future. The BM [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="schoolname">School of Business</h3>
<h3><em>Graphic Communications Technology</em></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The world of printed communications is expanding and evolving at a rapid pace. Traditional print products are supplemented by digital delivery and technology advances in high-tech digital imaging. Graphic communications companies need highly skilled individuals and BM College graduates are driving print media into the future.</p>
<p>The BM College Graphic Communications Technology (GTEC) diploma program provides students with the knowledge and skills to succeed in the business of digital imaging. In this program, you will design and produce marketing materials such as posters, large format signage, labels, brochures, books, and other finished products that organizations need to communicate with a connected and informed audience. You learn the latest graphic design software, business processes, art direction, production management, and how to operate high-tech imaging and finishing technologies.</p>
<p>As a BM College Graphic Communications student, you learn these career-ready skills:</p>
<ul>
<li>Devise business and marketing strategies incorporating print media</li>
<li>Use the latest graphic design software for effective visual communication</li>
<li>Design and create a variety of printed media projects</li>
<li>Use fonts and typography professionally</li>
<li>Operate many different high-tech imaging technologies</li>
<li>Use modern finishing techniques to complete real-world projects</li>
</ul>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">BM College GRAPHIC COMMUNICATIONS TECHNOLOGY</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>BM College Credential:</strong></td>
<td>BM College Diploma</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Length:</strong></td>
<td>2 years, Full-time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Start:</strong></td>
<td>September</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Number of Courses:</strong></td>
<td>36 courses, 119 credits</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total Tuition/Cost:</strong></td>
<td>Learn about Tuition &amp; Fees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Job Placements:</strong></td>
<td>2 weeks, 5 days a week<br />
6 weeks, 5 days a week</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>1st Year Entry:</strong></td>
<td>View Requirements</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Print &amp; Imaging Job Placements</h3>
<p>You will participate in a two week work experience at the end of the first year of study and a six week job placement in your graduating year. You will work with an established company to demonstrate your job ready skills and develop connections in the design, print imaging and publishing industries.</p>
<h3>A Career in Printed Media</h3>
<p>Graduates of the BM College Graphic Communications program have extensive experience in operating, the latest in high-tech imaging systems. Graduates get hands on experience with digital, ink-jet, lithographic and flexographic processes in our modern lab. Design, print, large format, digital, label, and packaging companies are all hiring from the Graphic Communications Technology program.</p>
<p>Entry-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Entry-level Press Operator</li>
<li>Preflight Operator</li>
<li>Print Estimator</li>
<li>Bindery Operator</li>
</ul>
<p>Mid-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Print Shop Manager</li>
<li>Printing Press Operator</li>
<li>Commercial Printing Plant Manager</li>
<li>Account Manager</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/graphic-communications-technology-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital Animation</title>
		<link>/digital-animation-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 07:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7752</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Business Digital Animation The BM College Digital Animation program prepares students to work in the gaming, film, and television industries. The program is broken down into series of collaborative courses that focus on skills that blend traditional art with high-end technology through several industry standard applications and techniques. Trained and supervised by industry [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="schoolname">School of Business</h3>
<h3><em>Digital Animation</em></h3>
<p>The BM College Digital Animation program prepares students to work in the gaming, film, and television industries. The program is broken down into series of collaborative courses that focus on skills that blend traditional art with high-end technology through several industry standard applications and techniques. Trained and supervised by industry professional instructors, students acquire both creative, design, and technical skills that prepare them for the demanding fields in these industries. Our successful graduates have been working in a variety of 3D modeling and animation positions at game production studios, video production companies, and design studios nationwide and around the world. The work of some of our graduates could be found in productions of game and films studios such as: Electronic Arts, Radical, Microsoft game studios, Bioware, Nerd-Corps, The Embassy, A.C.R.O.N.Y.M. Games, Capcom, Rainmaker, Eidos, and Pixar.</p>
<p>BM College Digital Animation students learn to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Design and create concept art for 3D models</li>
<li>Develop a storyboard for animation</li>
<li>Conceptualize characters and props</li>
<li>Stage a virtual environments and scene</li>
<li>Use industry standard 3D applications to transform the concept art into 3D assets</li>
<li>Create 2D and 3D animations</li>
<li>Design and produce textures for character and props</li>
<li>Sculpt and create high detail models</li>
<li>Create realistic textures and lighting</li>
<li>Design and optimize 3D assets for game production</li>
<li>Create and setup a game level in industry standard engines</li>
<li>Create film quality CG objects</li>
<li>Render and composite an industry standard professional demo reel</li>
</ul>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">BM College DIGITAL ANIMATION CERTIFICATE</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>BM College Credential:</strong></td>
<td>BM College Certificate</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Length:</strong></td>
<td>1 year, Full-time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Start:</strong></td>
<td>October &amp; April</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Location:</strong></td>
<td>London Campus</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Number of Courses:</strong></td>
<td>20 courses, 69 credits</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total Tuition/Cost:</strong></td>
<td>Learn about Tuition &amp; Fees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Major Project:</strong></td>
<td>3D modeling/Animation Demo Reel</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Animation Demo Reel</h3>
<p>As a final project, students complete a high quality 3D modeling and/or animation demo reel that can lead to jobs in the gaming, film and animation industries locally and abroad. In addition to creating a demo reel, students learn how to prepare for the job market by writing resumes, working on interview skills, networking techniques, public speaking, and presentation skills towards landing a job in the entertainment industry.</p>
<h3>Digital Animation Jobs &amp; Careers</h3>
<p>Graduates of the BM College Digital Animation certificate program develop a strong appreciation for game, film and animation production pipeline that includes: Concept design, project planning, 3D modeling, texturing, rigging, animating, lighting, rendering, and compositing. During the intense year, students gain valuable skills that lead them to a wide variety of digital animation job opportunities.</p>
<p>Entry-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>3D Animator</li>
<li>Character Modeler</li>
<li>VFX Artist</li>
<li>CG Artist</li>
</ul>
<p>Mid-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creative Director</li>
<li>Technical Director</li>
<li>Senior Animator</li>
<li>Team Lead</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Design Essentials</title>
		<link>/design-essentials/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 07:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7750</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Business Design Essentials &#160; The BM College Design Essentials certificate program is a one year program in partnership with Emily Carr University where creative students will develop their skills to become well rounded graphic design professionals. You will receive a solid foundation in practical design skills, desktop publishing, and web software skills. Graduates [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="schoolname">School of Business</h3>
<h3><em>Design Essentials</em></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The BM College Design Essentials certificate program is a one year program in partnership with Emily Carr University where creative students will develop their skills to become well rounded graphic design professionals. You will receive a solid foundation in practical design skills, desktop publishing, and web software skills. Graduates work in design studios, advertising agencies, and run their own design companies. This program runs two nights a week, one full weekend day, and one additional night a month.</p>
<p>BM College Design Essentials students learn to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Use the current version of the Adobe Creative Suite</li>
<li>Apply typography in print and online</li>
<li>Design logos and product packaging</li>
<li>Develop consistent corporate branding</li>
<li>Plan production schedules and project timelines</li>
</ul>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">BM College DESIGN ESSENTIALS CERTIFICATE</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>BM College Credential:</strong></td>
<td>BM College Certificate</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Length:</strong></td>
<td>1 year, Full-time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Start:</strong></td>
<td>October &amp; April</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Schedule:</strong></td>
<td>
<ul>
<li>2 nights a week</li>
<li>1 weekend full day</li>
<li>1 additional night per month</li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Location:</strong></td>
<td>Tacoma Campus &amp; Emily Carr</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Number of Courses:</strong></td>
<td>27 courses, 61.5 credits</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total Tuition/Cost:</strong></td>
<td>Learn about Tuition &amp; Fees</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Graphic Design Portfolio</h3>
<p>Most employers and potential clients want to see examples of past work. You will create both print and online portfolios to show potential employers or clients.</p>
<h3>Graphic Design Jobs &amp; Careers</h3>
<p>Graduates of the BM College Design Essentials program have designed marketing materials, corporate logos, and product packaging. Students gain many valuable skills that can lead to a wide variety of design job opportunities.</p>
<p>Entry-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Graphic Designer</li>
<li>Graphic Artist</li>
<li>Freelance Designer</li>
<li>Junior Designer</li>
</ul>
<p>Mid-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Senior Graphic Designer</li>
<li>Creative Director</li>
<li>Art Director</li>
<li>Brand Manager</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Aided Design (CAD) Technology</title>
		<link>/computer-aided-design-cad-technology/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 07:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7748</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Computer Aided Design (CAD) Technology Design Your Future A selection of part-time studies courses will be offered that will lead to an Associate Certificate in Computer Aided Design Technology. Computer Aided Design (CAD) tools are being increasingly used in engineering and architectural fields. As well, CAD is finding applications in other areas such as facilities management [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="programname">Computer Aided Design (CAD) Technology</h3>
<h4 id="tagline">Design Your Future</h4>
<p>A selection of part-time studies courses will be offered that will lead to an <strong>Associate Certificate in Computer Aided Design Technology</strong>. Computer Aided Design (CAD) tools are being increasingly used in engineering and architectural fields. As well, CAD is finding applications in other areas such as facilities management and interior design.</p>
<p>The Associate Certificate program is intended for:</p>
<ul>
<li>draftspersons, technicians or individuals who are skilled in a technical field who need to develop their CAD proficiency</li>
<li>individuals who require a formalization of their technical abilities in CAD</li>
</ul>
<p>The associate certificate program courses are taught at a level that assumes students have completed senior secondary school math, science and English or equivalent.</p>
<p>To be awarded an Associate Certificate in Computer Aided Design Technology, the student must complete 9.0 credits of required courses and 12.0 credits of elective courses for a total of 21.0 credits.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Business Information Technology Management</title>
		<link>/business-information-technology-management/</link>
		<comments>/business-information-technology-management/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 07:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7746</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Business Business Information Technology Management &#160; The BM College Business Information Technology Management (BITMAN) Diploma program combines in-demand technical computer skills with practical business knowledge to solve unique business issues. Not only will you develop computer information systems, but you will also have the skills to grow and develop technology-based businesses. Graduates can [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="schoolname">School of Business</div>
<h3><em>Business Information Technology Management</em></h3>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The BM College Business Information Technology Management (BITMAN) Diploma program combines in-demand technical computer skills with practical business knowledge to solve unique business issues. Not only will you develop computer information systems, but you will also have the skills to grow and develop technology-based businesses. Graduates can immediately apply their information technology and business skills in a wide range of industries and companies.</p>
<p>BM College Business Information Technology Management students learn to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Design business solutions</li>
<li>Manage complex projects</li>
<li>Integrate business processes with ERP software</li>
<li>Build e-commerce websites, databases, and networks</li>
<li>Use Microsoft Access, .NET, SQL, XML</li>
</ul>
<h3>BM College BUSINESS INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY MANAGEMENT</h3>
<table width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><strong>BM College Credential:</strong></td>
<td>BM College Diploma</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Length:</strong></td>
<td>2 years, Full-time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Start:</strong></td>
<td>September</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Number of Courses:</strong></td>
<td>33 courses, 115.5 credits</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total Tuition/Cost:</strong></td>
<td>Learn about Tuition &amp; Fees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Business Consulting Project:</strong></td>
<td>10 weeks, 2 days a week</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>1st Year Entry:</strong></td>
<td>View Requirements</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Advanced Placement:</strong></td>
<td>View Requirements</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Laddering Options:</strong></td>
<td>Bachelor of Business Administration BBA Degree</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Business Consulting Project</h3>
<p>Business Information Technology Management students undertake a 10 week Business Consulting Project in their final term. Students work in groups of 2-3 and spend two days a week developing a solution to a real problem for a company. The student teams collect and analyze data, create recommendations, and present their findings to company management.</p>
<h3>Professional Designations</h3>
<p>Graduates of the Business Information Technology Management Diploma program can pursue additional career building opportunities. Graduates are eligible to enter the following professional designation programs:</p>
<ul>
<li>Certified Associate in Project Management CAPM</li>
<li>SAP TERP10 Certification</li>
<li>Certified in Management CIM</li>
<li>Professional Manager P. Mgr.</li>
</ul>
<h3>IT &amp; Business Jobs &amp; Careers</h3>
<p>Graduates of the Business Information Technology Management Diploma program have a strong foundation in both information technology and business. Grads are able to apply their IT and business skills in a wide variety of job opportunities.</p>
<p>Entry-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Business Analyst</li>
<li>Associate Project Manager</li>
<li>Web Designer/Developer</li>
<li>Programmer/Database Administrator</li>
</ul>
<p>Mid-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Project Manager</li>
<li>IT/ERP Consultant</li>
<li>IT Manager/Team Leader</li>
<li>Internet Marketer/Entrepren</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/business-information-technology-management/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Applied Computer Information Systems (ACIS)</title>
		<link>/applied-computer-information-systems-acis/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Technologies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7744</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Computing and Academic Studies Applied Computer Information Systems (ACIS) Learn to use Information Technology Learn computer information systems (CIS) foundations and how these technologies are used and managed in a business environment. This program is aimed at two audiences; individuals currently working in information systems with no formal credentials and those interested in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>School of Computing and Academic Studies<br />
<em>Applied Computer Information Systems (ACIS)</em></h3>
<p>Learn to use Information Technology</p>
<p>Learn computer information systems (CIS) foundations and how these technologies are used and managed in a business environment.</p>
<p>This program is aimed at two audiences; individuals currently working in information systems with no formal credentials and those interested in a CIS foundation before moving on to higher education in computing.</p>
<p>This hands-on credential is the second step in laddering toward the Computer Systems Technology Diploma (CST/PTS).</p>
<p>If your end goal is the Diploma, then you should complete Applied Software Development (ASD) before starting this credential.</p>
<p>Start by learning to be an expert end-user of a personal computer, then become proficient in typical office applications, followed by an in-depth understanding of relational database design and data modeling.</p>
<p>A wide variety of electives are offered to suit individual interests including: accounting software, IT project management, object oriented programming and web development.</p>
<p>Students may also chose electives in expert level word processing, spreadsheets, business and technical communication, plus business intelligence for data mining.</p>
<p>Successful participants will have acquired a solid understanding of the technical foundations in business information systems.</p>
<p>ACIS graduates not moving on to the CST Diploma may choose to continue on to Applied Database Administration and Design.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Applied Computer Applications (ACA)</title>
		<link>/applied-computer-applications-aca-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Technologies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7742</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Computing and Academic Studies Learn to be an expert PC user Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools. School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications. For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>School of Computing and Academic Studies</h1>
<h3>Learn to be an expert PC user</h3>
<p>Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools.</p>
<p>School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications.</p>
<p>For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding of current versions of MS Office, this program provides hands-on experience. It is designed for both new and existing personal computer users.</p>
<p>Students will have the confidence to master a variety of future application software as versions change.</p>
<p>Starting with Computer Concepts, students learn to properly use a Windows PC before moving on to either Word or Excel. Access and Web Development and Design complete the core.</p>
<p>Electives range from MS PowerPoint, Business Intelligence with Crystal Reports, MS Access Development and Simply Accounting and Business and Technical Communication.</p>
<p>Students who successfully complete this program will also be prepared to challenge the associated MOS, Microsoft Office Specialist exams, for an additional fee.</p>
<p>Graduates of this Associate Certificate may choose to continue on to the Applied Web Development, Associate Certificate.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Applied Computer Applications (ACA)</title>
		<link>/applied-computer-applications-aca/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Technologies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Learn to be an expert PC user Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools. School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications. For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding of current versions of MS Office, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learn to be an expert PC user</p>
<p>Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools.</p>
<p>School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications.</p>
<p>For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding of current versions of MS Office, this program provides hands-on experience. It is designed for both new and existing personal computer users.</p>
<p>Students will have the confidence to master a variety of future application software as versions change.</p>
<p>Starting with Computer Concepts, students learn to properly use a Windows PC before moving on to either Word or Excel. Access and Web Development and Design complete the core.</p>
<p>Electives range from MS PowerPoint, Business Intelligence with Crystal Reports, MS Access Development and Simply Accounting and Business and Technical Communication.</p>
<p>Students who successfully complete this program will also be prepared to challenge the associated MOS, Microsoft Office Specialist exams, for an additional fee.</p>
<p>Graduates of this Associate Certificate may choose to continue on to the Applied Web Development, Associate Certificate.</p>
<p>Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Digital Animation</title>
		<link>/digital-animation/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 17:22:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Design]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7520</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[BM College Digital Animation Certificate Full-time     Certificate The BM College Digital Animation program prepares students to work in the gaming, film, and television industries. The program is broken down into series of collaborative courses that focus on skills that blend traditional art with high-end technology through several industry standard applications and techniques. Trained and supervised by [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">BM College Digital Animation Certificate</h1>
<p>Full-time     Certificate</p>
<p>The BM College Digital Animation program prepares students to work in the gaming, film, and television industries. The program is broken down into series of collaborative courses that focus on skills that blend traditional art with high-end technology through several industry standard applications and techniques. Trained and supervised by industry professional instructors, students acquire both creative, design, and technical skills that prepare them for the demanding fields in these industries. Our successful graduates have been working in a variety of 3D modeling and animation positions at game production studios, video production companies, and design studios nationwide and around the world. The work of some of our graduates could be found in productions of game and films studios such as: Electronic Arts, Radical, Microsoft game studios, Bioware, Nerd-Corps, The Embassy, A.C.R.O.N.Y.M. Games, Capcom, Rainmaker, Eidos, and Pixar.</p>
<p>BM College Digital Animation students learn to:</p>
<ul>
<li>Design and create concept art for 3D models</li>
<li>Develop a storyboard for animation</li>
<li>Conceptualize characters and props</li>
<li>Stage a virtual environments and scene</li>
<li>Use industry standard 3D applications to transform the concept art into 3D assets</li>
<li>Create 2D and 3D animations</li>
<li>Design and produce textures for character and props</li>
<li>Sculpt and create high detail models</li>
<li>Create realistic textures and lighting</li>
<li>Design and optimize 3D assets for game production</li>
<li>Create and setup a game level in industry standard engines</li>
<li>Create film quality CG objects</li>
<li>Render and composite an industry standard professional demo reel</li>
</ul>
<table class="gentable" width="100%">
<tbody>
<tr>
<th colspan="2">BM College DIGITAL ANIMATION CERTIFICATE</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>BM College Credential:</strong></td>
<td>BM College Certificate</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Length:</strong></td>
<td>1 year, Full-time</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Program Start:</strong></td>
<td>October &amp; April</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Location:</strong></td>
<td>Tacoma Campus</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Number of Courses:</strong></td>
<td>20 courses, 69 credits</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Total Tuition/Cost:</strong></td>
<td>Learn about Tuition &amp; Fees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><strong>Major Project:</strong></td>
<td>3D modeling/Animation Demo Reel</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h3>Animation Demo Reel</h3>
<p>As a final project, students complete a high quality 3D modeling and/or animation demo reel that can lead to jobs in the gaming, film and animation industries locally and abroad. In addition to creating a demo reel, students learn how to prepare for the job market by writing resumes, working on interview skills, networking techniques, public speaking, and presentation skills towards landing a job in the entertainment industry.</p>
<h3>Digital Animation Jobs &amp; Careers</h3>
<p>Graduates of the BM College Digital Animation certificate program develop a strong appreciation for game, film and animation production pipeline that includes: Concept design, project planning, 3D modeling, texturing, rigging, animating, lighting, rendering, and compositing. During the intense year, students gain valuable skills that lead them to a wide variety of digital animation job opportunities.</p>
<p>Entry-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>3D Animator</li>
<li>Character Modeler</li>
<li>VFX Artist</li>
<li>CG Artist</li>
</ul>
<p>Mid-Level Positions:</p>
<ul>
<li>Creative Director</li>
<li>Technical Director</li>
<li>Senior Animator</li>
<li>Team Lead</li>
</ul>
<p>Programs and courses are subject to change without notice</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
