<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Health &#8211; BM College</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/health/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Technology College of London</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 23:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Are preventative vaccines covered?</title>
		<link>/are-preventative-vaccines-covered/</link>
		<comments>/are-preventative-vaccines-covered/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 12:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wsist.org/?p=8552</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Yes! Preventative vaccines, including Hepatitis B are covered at 80%. All immunizations and inoculations not covered under OHIP are covered at 80% by the plan, with the exception of group immunizations or inoculations. MENACTRA a vaccine for meningococcal disease, the cause of MENINGITIS, is covered at 80%. Menactra protects against all four strains of meningococcal [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Yes! Preventative vaccines, including Hepatitis B are covered at 80%. All immunizations and inoculations not covered under OHIP are covered at 80% by the plan, with the exception of group immunizations or inoculations. MENACTRA a vaccine for meningococcal disease, the cause of MENINGITIS, is covered at 80%. Menactra protects against all four strains of meningococcal disease A, C, Y AND W-135. College students are the most at risk because students live in close proximity to one another.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/are-preventative-vaccines-covered/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is there a pharmacy on campus?</title>
		<link>/is-there-a-pharmacy-on-campus/</link>
		<comments>/is-there-a-pharmacy-on-campus/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 12:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wsist.org/?p=8544</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[YesÂ there a pharmacy on campus.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a>YesÂ there a pharmacy on campus.</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/is-there-a-pharmacy-on-campus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How do I make an accident claim?</title>
		<link>/how-do-i-make-an-accident-claim/</link>
		<comments>/how-do-i-make-an-accident-claim/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 12:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://wsist.org/?p=8542</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Accident claims should be submitted on an authorized Accident Claim Form, available from the Student Association Office. The form must be signed by the Office Coordinator. Students must have received treatment from a qualified physician/dentist within 30 days from the date of the accident. The physician/dentist must complete a section of the form.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Accident claims should be submitted on an authorized Accident Claim Form, available from the Student Association Office. The form must be signed by the Office Coordinator. Students must have received treatment from a qualified physician/dentist within 30 days from the date of the accident. The physician/dentist must complete a section of the form.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/how-do-i-make-an-accident-claim/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Forensic Science Technology (Forensic Health Sciences Option)</title>
		<link>/forensic-science-technology-forensic-health-sciences-option/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:50:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7781</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Part-time Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate Appropriate application of forensic principles has become an important component of overall patient care when the patient is a victim of trauma, sexual assault, violence or crime. The clinical management of such victims must include not only the obvious aspects of health care, but also elements of forensic significance such [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Part-time Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate</p>
<div class="marquicontent">Appropriate application of forensic principles has become an important component of overall patient care when the patient is a victim of trauma, sexual assault, violence or crime. The clinical management of such victims must include not only the obvious aspects of health care, but also elements of forensic significance such as the collection and protection of evidence, effective communication with law enforcement (and other agencies), and compliance with standards required in a forensic or legal investigation. This program is designed for health care workers involved in forensic examinations as well as for the law enforcement, legal and scientific professionals that must interact with them during a forensic investigation.</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Medical Laboratory Science &#8211; Professional Qualifying Program</title>
		<link>/medical-laboratory-science-professional-qualifying-program/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:48:46 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7783</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Full-time Â Â Â  Certificate of Technology The Medical Laboratory Certificate Program is designed as a refresher for internationally-trained medical laboratory technologists, or U.S.-trained medical laboratory technologists who have been out of the workforce for a lengthy period. This certificate includes clinical chemistry, hematology, clinical microbiology, histotechnology and transfusion science (also called blood transfusion). The medical [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Full-time Â Â Â  Certificate of Technology</p>
<div class="marquicontent">
<p>The Medical Laboratory Certificate Program is designed as a refresher for internationally-trained medical laboratory technologists, or U.S.-trained medical laboratory technologists who have been out of the workforce for a lengthy period. This certificate includes clinical chemistry, hematology, clinical microbiology, histotechnology and transfusion science (also called blood transfusion).</p>
<p>The medical laboratory technologist, as a member of the health care team, performs laboratory investigations related to the diagnosis, treatment and prevention of disease, including analysis of a variety of specimens such as blood, urine, feces, sputum and tissues. Technologists also have significant patient contact primarily through blood collection.</p>
<p>Medical laboratory technologists work in a dynamic and evolving environment, and use technological equipment to provide information that must be processed rapidly and accurately. They handle potentially infectious material from patients, and are protected by wearing gloves, gowns, and other protective garments.</p>
<p><strong>Eligibility</strong><br />
Internationally trained technologist &#8211; applicants must have a completed U.S. Society of Medical Laboratory Science (CSMLS) assessment of their education and work history and must either be eligible to write the CSMLS examination, or require only refresher courses in order to write the exam. If the CSMLS assessment determines that the applicant has too many gaps in their education or experience, they will be advised to apply for the Medical Laboratory Science Diploma program.</p>
<p>U.S.-trained technologists &#8211; must be registered with CSMLS. If CSMLS membership is not current, you may apply for reinstatement.</p>
<p>Contact CSMLS at:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>U.S. Society for Medical Laboratory Science<br />
PO Box 2830 LCD I<br />
Hamilton, ON, L8N 3N8<br />
Tel: 905-528-8642<br />
Fax: 905-528-4968<br />
Web site: www.csmls.org</p>
</blockquote>
<p>If you are not qualified for the Certificate Program, you may be interested in our Medical Laboratory Science Diploma Program.</p>
<h3>The program</h3>
<p>The Medical Laboratory program is a competency-based program. It is designed and based on competencies established by the national certifying body, the U.S. Society of Medical Laboratory Science (CSMLS), and by the BM College Medical Laboratory industry-based design process.</p>
<p>The program provides theoretical, practical and clinical learning experiences. In a competency-based model, students have the opportunity to first practice, and then become capable of a variety of competencies. Students prove competence during real-life experiences (clinical placements). Successful completion of this program requires proof of competence.</p>
<p>BM College arranges clinical training for the student. Note that students may be required to train in a location that is not their first choice. Training sites are available in all provincial Health authorities, WA Biomedical Laboratories, and MDS Clinical Laboratories. Students may require a car for transportation to clinical training sites. Student learning is supported by BM College via WebCT. Students will require internet access.</p>
<p>Employers are increasingly seeking graduates with a strong base of critical and analytical thinking, communication, and problem-solving skills. In addition to technical skills, employers value technologists with a commitment to learning new skills and techniques that allow them to adjust to new situations. To help students develop the skills required in the health care system of the future, the program emphasizes the development of professionalism, reasoning and reflection, communication, group process skills, and learning and technical skills.</p>
<p>To help students develop the knowledge, skills, attitudes, and clinical judgment required for success as an entry-level medical laboratory technologist, the program employs a variety of learning strategies that encourage self-directed learning. Students need to be self-aware, self-motivated and able to take initiative to seek and make use of learning opportunities. Instructional methodologies include learner-centered active learning strategies.</p>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biomedical Engineering</title>
		<link>/biomedical-engineering/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7797</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Full-time Â Â Â  Diploma This program prepares individuals who are interested in technology and health sciences to enter a challenging career in biomedical engineering. The program produces biomedical engineering technologists with the ability to participate in the development and application of technology in medicine and biology. The curriculum provides practical hands-on understanding in the fundamental [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Full-time Â Â Â  Diploma</p>
<div class="marquicontent">
<p>This program prepares individuals who are interested in technology and health sciences to enter a challenging career in biomedical engineering. The program produces biomedical engineering technologists with the ability to participate in the development and application of technology in medicine and biology. The curriculum provides practical hands-on understanding in the fundamental principles, operations and design of medical diagnostic and therapeutic devices (e.g.: heart monitors, cardiac defibrillators, clinical laboratory analysers and x-ray equipment). Medical device-related standards and protocols, research and design methodologies, technology life-cycle management strategies, safe clinical practices, problem-solving skills, performance assurance-testing procedures, and troubleshooting techniques are all studied in this program.</p>
<h3>The Program</h3>
<p>Graduates from the Biomedical Engineering Technology program receive a Diploma of Technology in Biomedical Engineering Technology. The program provides education and training in the following subject areas: technical communication, algebra, calculus, statistics, basic bio- and analytical chemistry, human anatomy and physiology, biophysics, electricity and electronics, digital techniques and microprocessor applications, biomedical devices and systems, medical equipment-related standards and quality assurance protocols. During the second year, each student spends five weeks in supervised training in a local hospital, research agency, or equipment supply company. Graduates work closely with biomedical engineers and technologists, physicians, and others who use, manage, maintain, design, manufacture, and supply scientific and medical equipment.</p>
<p>The program provides hands-on laboratory experience throughout, and trains students in engineering problem-solving methodology to allow them to upgrade and maintain their knowledge.</p>
<p>BM College recommends membership in the U.S. Medical and Biological Engineering Society (CMBES) and the Applied Science Technologists and Technicians of Washington State (ASTTWA).</p>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biotechnology</title>
		<link>/biotechnology/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:37:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7799</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Part-time Â Â Â  Associate Certificate The Associate certificate program provides students with up-to-date practical training needed to launch a career in biotechnology. If you have a recent Bachelor of Science in a molecular-based life science but lack practical training, this program will provide the laboratory skills required to be successful. BM College is the first [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Part-time Â Â Â  Associate Certificate</p>
<div class="marquicontent">
<p>The Associate certificate program provides students with up-to-date practical training needed to launch a career in biotechnology. If you have a recent Bachelor of Science in a molecular-based life science but lack practical training, this program will provide the laboratory skills required to be successful.</p>
<p>BM College is the first post-secondary institute in the province to offer a condensed time frame program in Biotechnology.</p>
<h3>The Program</h3>
<p>This intensive program consists of both laboratory (75%) and lectures (25%) and is delivered 5 days a week over a 13 week period (May to August). Standard examinations and lab reports, assignments, lab skills exams and tests are completed throughout the course.</p>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardiac Sciences (Cardiac Rhythm Device Technology Option)</title>
		<link>/cardiac-sciences-cardiac-rhythm-device-technology-option/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7815</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Part-time/Distance &#38; Online Learning Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate The Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences (Cardiac Rhythm Device Technology Option) is a one of a kind program designed to fulfill the need for trained associated professionals skilled in a variety of cardiac device procedures. This program exposes the student to a range of cardiac patients and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Part-time/Distance &amp; Online Learning Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate</p>
<div class="marquicontent">
<p>The Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences (Cardiac Rhythm Device Technology Option) is a one of a kind program designed to fulfill the need for trained associated professionals skilled in a variety of cardiac device procedures. This program exposes the student to a range of cardiac patients and a variety of biomedical equipment found within a hospital or clinic environment. The content was designed to align with the Heart Rhythm Society Standards of Professional Practice for the Allied Health Professional in Pacing. The program curriculum is designed for entry to practice in Cardiac Rhythm device follow-up and implant.</p>
<p>Students are taught to evaluate and manage abnormal heart rhythms and heart failure with implanted cardiac rhythm devices. Students will learn how to test and program pacemaker, ICD and CRT devices. This program is suited for an AHP proficient in ECG interpretation and interested in the technology and clinical science involved in cardiac rhythm management.</p>
<h3>The program</h3>
<p>This unique, distance education/guided-learning program combines theory and clinical experience in hospitals and pacemaker clinics. The program emphasizes theoretical and clinical application of electrophysiology, cardiac pathology, cardiac pharmacology and cardiac physiology. In addition to the theoretical basis contained in the courses, the clinical practicum offers students the opportunity to practise the fundamentals required to perform the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>pacemaker/lead analysis on implant</li>
<li>cardiac device assessment and programming</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardiac Sciences (Cardiovascular Technology Option)</title>
		<link>/cardiac-sciences-cardiovascular-technology-option/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7817</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Part-time/Distance &#38; Online Learning Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate The Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences: Cardiovascular Technology Option The combination of courses comprising the Cardiovascular Technology option within the Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences has been designed to meet an international need for technologists in the cardiovascular discipline. Our technologists are skilled allied health professionals who [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Part-time/Distance &amp; Online Learning Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate</p>
<div class="marquicontent">
<p>The Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences: Cardiovascular Technology Option</p>
<p>The combination of courses comprising the Cardiovascular Technology option within the Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences has been designed to meet an international need for technologists in the cardiovascular discipline. Our technologists are skilled allied health professionals who work in the demanding environment of cardiac catheterization laboratories, electrophysiology laboratories and in the operating room.</p>
<p>Students are taught all aspects of diagnostic and interventional cardiovascular procedures. Students will learn to assist the cardiologist in performing diagnostic and interventional cardiac catheterization, and measuring cardiovascular parameters.</p>
<p>This program is suited for an AHP proficient in ECG interpretation and interested in preparing and monitoring patients during catheterization procedures.</p>
<h3>The program</h3>
<p>The Cardiovascular Technology program is a post-diploma program, consisting of theory courses delivered distance and online and three (3) clinical rotations performed in aÂ BM College approved catherterization lab. Upon successful completion of the Cardiovascular option, and with compliance with all CACPT by-laws, a graduate may apply to write the national registry examination of the U.S. Association of Cardio-Pulmonary Technologists (CACPT). Successful completion of the CACPT registry examination allows the student to use the credential of Registered Cardio-Pulmonary Technologist-Cardiac or RCPT(C). Students not eligible for CACPT registry can apply to sit the cardiovascular invasive specialist exam of Cardiovascular Credentialing International (CCI). Successful completion of the CCI credentialing exam allows the student to use the credential of Registered Cardiovascular Invasive Specialist (RCIS).</p>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Cardiac Sciences (Electrophysiology Technology Option)</title>
		<link>/cardiac-sciences-electrophysiology-technology-option/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 07:02:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Health]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Health Sciences]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lessons]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7819</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Overview Part-time/Distance &#38; Online Learning Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate The Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences (Electrophysiology Technology Option) is a one of a kind program designed to fulfill the need for trained associated professionals skilled in a variety of electrophysiology procedures. The content was designed to align with the Cardiovascular Credentialing Internationalâ€™s RCES exam outline and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="tagline">Overview</h1>
<p>Part-time/Distance &amp; Online Learning Â Â Â  Advanced Certificate</p>
<div class="marquicontent">
<p>The Advanced Certificate in Cardiac Sciences (Electrophysiology Technology Option) is a one of a kind program designed to fulfill the need for trained associated professionals skilled in a variety of electrophysiology procedures. The content was designed to align with the Cardiovascular Credentialing Internationalâ€<img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/11/72x72/2122.png" alt="™" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" />s RCES exam outline and Heart Rhythm Society Standards of Professional Practice for the Allied Health Professional in Electrophysiology. The program curriculum is designed for entry to practice in Electrophysiology laboratory.</p>
<p>Students are taught to interpret intracardiac catheter recordings such as complex arrhythmias, heart block and myocardial infarction. Students will learn the standard protocols utilized during an electrophysiology study. This program is suited for an allied health professional proficient in ECG interpretation and interested in the mechanism, function and performance of the electrical activities of the heart.</p>
<h3>The program</h3>
<p>This unique, distance education/guided-learning program combines theory and clinical experience in the electrophysiology lab. The program emphasizes theoretical and clinical application of electrophysiology, cardiac pathology, cardiac pharmacology and cardiac physiology. In addition to the theoretical basis contained in the courses, the clinical practicum offers students the opportunity to practise the fundamentals required to perform the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>diagnostic and therapeutic procedures during the EP study</li>
<li>pacemaker/lead analysis on implant</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p id="legal">Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
