<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Software Development &#8211; BM College</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/computingit/softwaredevelopment/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Technology College of London</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 23:04:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>Applied Computer Information Systems (ACIS)</title>
		<link>/applied-computer-information-systems-acis/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Technologies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7744</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Computing and Academic Studies Applied Computer Information Systems (ACIS) Learn to use Information Technology Learn computer information systems (CIS) foundations and how these technologies are used and managed in a business environment. This program is aimed at two audiences; individuals currently working in information systems with no formal credentials and those interested in [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>School of Computing and Academic Studies<br />
<em>Applied Computer Information Systems (ACIS)</em></h3>
<p>Learn to use Information Technology</p>
<p>Learn computer information systems (CIS) foundations and how these technologies are used and managed in a business environment.</p>
<p>This program is aimed at two audiences; individuals currently working in information systems with no formal credentials and those interested in a CIS foundation before moving on to higher education in computing.</p>
<p>This hands-on credential is the second step in laddering toward the Computer Systems Technology Diploma (CST/PTS).</p>
<p>If your end goal is the Diploma, then you should complete Applied Software Development (ASD) before starting this credential.</p>
<p>Start by learning to be an expert end-user of a personal computer, then become proficient in typical office applications, followed by an in-depth understanding of relational database design and data modeling.</p>
<p>A wide variety of electives are offered to suit individual interests including: accounting software, IT project management, object oriented programming and web development.</p>
<p>Students may also chose electives in expert level word processing, spreadsheets, business and technical communication, plus business intelligence for data mining.</p>
<p>Successful participants will have acquired a solid understanding of the technical foundations in business information systems.</p>
<p>ACIS graduates not moving on to the CST Diploma may choose to continue on to Applied Database Administration and Design.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Applied Computer Applications (ACA)</title>
		<link>/applied-computer-applications-aca-2/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Technologies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7742</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[School of Computing and Academic Studies Learn to be an expert PC user Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools. School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications. For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>School of Computing and Academic Studies</h1>
<h3>Learn to be an expert PC user</h3>
<p>Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools.</p>
<p>School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications.</p>
<p>For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding of current versions of MS Office, this program provides hands-on experience. It is designed for both new and existing personal computer users.</p>
<p>Students will have the confidence to master a variety of future application software as versions change.</p>
<p>Starting with Computer Concepts, students learn to properly use a Windows PC before moving on to either Word or Excel. Access and Web Development and Design complete the core.</p>
<p>Electives range from MS PowerPoint, Business Intelligence with Crystal Reports, MS Access Development and Simply Accounting and Business and Technical Communication.</p>
<p>Students who successfully complete this program will also be prepared to challenge the associated MOS, Microsoft Office Specialist exams, for an additional fee.</p>
<p>Graduates of this Associate Certificate may choose to continue on to the Applied Web Development, Associate Certificate.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Applied Computer Applications (ACA)</title>
		<link>/applied-computer-applications-aca/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Application Training]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Web Technologies]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7738</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Learn to be an expert PC user Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools. School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications. For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding of current versions of MS Office, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Learn to be an expert PC user</p>
<p>Most jobs require the use a personal computer and proficiency in word processing, spreadsheets, presentations and reporting tools.</p>
<p>School of Computing offers several ways to acquire expert level skills in computer applications.</p>
<p>For those who want a deeper and more expert understanding of current versions of MS Office, this program provides hands-on experience. It is designed for both new and existing personal computer users.</p>
<p>Students will have the confidence to master a variety of future application software as versions change.</p>
<p>Starting with Computer Concepts, students learn to properly use a Windows PC before moving on to either Word or Excel. Access and Web Development and Design complete the core.</p>
<p>Electives range from MS PowerPoint, Business Intelligence with Crystal Reports, MS Access Development and Simply Accounting and Business and Technical Communication.</p>
<p>Students who successfully complete this program will also be prepared to challenge the associated MOS, Microsoft Office Specialist exams, for an additional fee.</p>
<p>Graduates of this Associate Certificate may choose to continue on to the Applied Web Development, Associate Certificate.</p>
<p>Programs and courses are subject to change without notice.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electrical and Computer Engineering Technology (Computer Control Option)</title>
		<link>/electrical-and-computer-engineering-technology-computer-control-option/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 06:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computer Hardware]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7732</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF ENERGY Electrical and Computer Engineering TechnologyComputer Control Option Note: This program is no longer accepting new applications for September 2014. Applications for readmission may be submitted. For more information, review the Program Entry page. The January 2015 intake will start accepting applications on June 2, 2014. Please check our list of programs that [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF ENERGY<br />
Electrical and Computer Engineering TechnologyComputer Control Option</p>
<p>Note: This program is no longer accepting new applications for September 2014. Applications for readmission may be submitted. For more information, review the Program Entry page.<br />
The January 2015 intake will start accepting applications on June 2, 2014.<br />
Please check our list of programs that may have space available or access our program database for a complete list of BM College programs.</p>
<p>The program</p>
<p>This broad-based program provides the necessary background for entry into a variety of areas in the electronics industry. Students will learn how to write software (for a personal computer, microcontroller and PIC) and design electronic circuitry to sense and control events. In the electronics industry, the combination of good programming and electronic circuit design skills is highly desirable, especially within the large number of companies involved in the design and development of control and data acquisition products.<br />
student in a lab<br />
Graduates of the Computer Control option may obtain a dual diploma in both Computer Control and Electrical Power and Industrial Control by completing Level 4 studies in the Electrical Power and Industrial Control option. Entry to this 2nd option is competitive.<br />
Careers</p>
<p>Graduates are employed in research and development, design, and manufacturing, working on a broad range of equipment including machinery, data networks, computers and peripheral devices, marine and sonar systems, traffic control systems, power-supply equipment, airline display systems, satellite data analysis systems, and theatre lighting-control systems. You might work in a structured environment doing maintenance or research, or in a fast-paced environment where you solve different technical problems every day, either alone or as part of a team.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Information Technology</title>
		<link>/computer-information-technology/</link>
		<comments>/computer-information-technology/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 05:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Networking & Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7724</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES Computer Information Technology Note: The September 2014 intake is now closed for new applications. Applications for advanced placement and readmission may be submitted. The next intake will start accepting applications on November 3, 2014. Please check our list of programs that may have space available or access our program [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES<br />
Computer Information Technology<br />
Note: The September 2014 intake is now closed for new applications. Applications for advanced placement and readmission may be submitted. The next intake will start accepting applications on November 3, 2014.</p>
<p>Please check our list of programs that may have space available or access our program database for a complete list of BM College programs.</p>
<p>Qualified IT professionals are in high demand. The Computer Information Technology (CIT) Diploma program is a unique two-year credential that prepares graduates for IT systems management/administration and computer-related careers.</p>
<p>The program</p>
<p>CIT students are introduced to a broad range of technologies including database, networking administration, web technologies and security. Graduates will be IT specialists responsible for planning, deployment, administration and configuration of computing infrastructures for organizations. Combined with core courses in communications, business, math and the real-world aspect of two industry projects students will develop the necessary confidence and expertise of an industry professional &#8211; in just two years!</p>
<p>An optional co-op education component of the CIT program provides students with substantial benefits given that employers are eager to hire graduates who have had some co-op experience. Co-op students may undertake four or eight month work placements commencing in May.</p>
<p>Diploma graduates from the CIT diploma program have the following skills:</p>
<p>Foundation skills: software processes and programming fundamentals, communications, business processes and project planning<br />
Database related skills: data modelling, database design, administration and management<br />
Computing infrastructure skills: network administration and security and information systems<br />
Internet related skills: web technologies and human computer interface.<br />
Continue your education</p>
<p>Diploma graduates may pursue a two year BM College Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems on a part-time or full-time basis.</p>
<p>Scheduled intake</p>
<p>September each year. Apply now!</p>
<p>Related programs</p>
<p>School of Computing part-time and full-time programs.</p>
<p>Video from June 2012 CST Diploma Info Session</p>
<p>Brian Pidcock, Associate Dean<br />
Download presentation [PDF, 5.0MB]
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/computer-information-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Systems (Network Security Administration Option)</title>
		<link>/computer-systems-network-security-administration-option-2/</link>
		<comments>/computer-systems-network-security-administration-option-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 05:17:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Networking & Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7722</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES Computer SystemsNetwork Security Administration Option Note: New admission procedures effective November 15, 2013. Review the instructions carefully. View summary of the changes The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems (CST B.Tech) is an applied career-enhancement degree designed to increase the depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer system [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES<br />
Computer SystemsNetwork Security Administration Option</p>
<p>Note: New admission procedures effective November 15, 2013. Review the instructions carefully. View summary of the changes</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems (CST B.Tech) is an applied career-enhancement degree designed to increase the depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer system technologists, and to assist them in widening their career opportunities or advancing in their career paths. Graduates are awarded a credential that is highly valued by the industry.</p>
<p>The CST B.Tech full-time program is also a two-year degree completion program for students who have graduated from a two-year diploma program in computing such as the BM College Computer Systems Technology (CST) or Computer Information Technology (CIT) program. Students who have completed other computing diploma or degree programs in an accredited college or university, whether locally or internationally, can usually be admitted into the program with only a few bridging courses.</p>
<p>The specialty areas for the September 2014 Intake are:</p>
<p>Network Security Administration<br />
Games Development<br />
The Network Security Administration Option is designed to prepare graduates to plan, manage and secure network infrastructures in business environments. The program includes knowledge and skill development in business communications and leadership, as well as the essential technical knowledge components, with a focus on establishing a set of advanced skills encompassing three key areas of network administration and network security.</p>
<p>The first component addresses the basic issues of network infrastructure, including the configuration, deployment and management of key network components such as servers and control devices. Also covered are the practices of securing systems and services, system monitoring for performance, and customizing kernels for specialized applications.</p>
<p>The second general component addresses the more advanced issues of deploying network defenses. Topics covered are the design and implementation of firewalls, Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems, and perimeter designs. Courses will provide practical skills in the area of network forensics and &#8220;real-world&#8221; network traffic analysis using a variety of tools.</p>
<p>The third general component primarily deals with network vulnerabilities and exploits. Students will acquire hands-on experience with network penetration tools and frameworks. Topics include network reconnaissance techniques, identifying vulnerabilities, and carrying out network penetration exercises. Attacks and exploits such as packet sniffing, social engineering, phishing, malware, covert channels, and Trojans will be covered. The use of Honeynets and Wargames in understanding how to mitigate network threats and vulnerabilities will be covered.</p>
<p>For more information on the CST BTech program please visit our full-time site and/or the part-time site.</p>
<p>This program is also offered in a part-time format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/computer-systems-network-security-administration-option-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Systems (Network Security Administration Option)</title>
		<link>/computer-systems-network-security-administration-option/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 05:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Networking & Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7720</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES Computer SystemsNetwork Security Administration Option Network Security Administration &#8211; Build Your Skills in Intrusion Detection, Attacks and Defenses Note: New admission procedures effective November 15, 2013. Review the instructions carefully. View summary of the changes The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES<br />
Computer SystemsNetwork Security Administration Option</p>
<p>Network Security Administration &#8211; Build Your Skills in Intrusion Detection, Attacks and Defenses</p>
<p>Note: New admission procedures effective November 15, 2013. Review the instructions carefully. View summary of the changes</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth and depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer professionals, assisting them in widening their job opportunities or advancing along their career paths. Graduates are awarded a credential that is highly valued by the industry.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology degree in Computer Systems has two components. The first component is made up 42.0 credits of technical courses and major projects. This includes core courses, specialty courses (depth in a specific area) and technical electives (breadth in additional areas). The major projects allow the student to apply specialty knowledge in a real-life project, study, or applied research project. The second component consists 18.0 credits of General Education and Management courses.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is offered in a flexible delivery format to serve the needs of working professionals. Candidates can take course loads ranging from a minimum of three courses per year to an equivalent of a full-time program of studies. Most courses are offered in the evening or on weekends. Some are offered online through Web-based courses or during the day (depending on demand). Applicants can apply to the program at any time through the year.</p>
<p>The Network Security Administration Option is designed to prepare graduates to plan, manage and secure network infrastructures in business environments. The program includes knowledge and skill development in business communications and leadership, as well as the essential technical knowledge components, with a focus on establishing a set of advanced skills encompassing three key areas of network administration and network security.</p>
<p>The first component addresses the basic issues of network infrastructure, including the configuration, deployment and management of key network components such as servers and control devices. Also covered are the practices of securing systems and services, system monitoring for performance, and customizing kernels for specialized applications.</p>
<p>The second general component addresses the more advanced issues of deploying network defenses. Topics covered are the design and implementation of firewalls, Intrusion Detection/Prevention Systems, and perimeter designs. Courses will provide practical skills in the area of network forensics and &#8220;real-world&#8221; network traffic analysis using a variety of tools.</p>
<p>The third general component primarily deals with network vulnerabilities and exploits. Students will acquire hands-on experience with network penetration tools and frameworks. Topics include network reconnaissance techniques, identifying vulnerabilities, and carrying out network penetration exercises. Attacks and exploits such as packet sniffing, social engineering, phishing, malware, covert channels, and Trojans will be covered. The use of Honeynets and Wargames in understanding how to mitigate network threats and vulnerabilities will be covered.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is also offered in a full-time format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Systems (Network Security Applications Development Option)</title>
		<link>/computer-systems-network-security-applications-development-option-2/</link>
		<comments>/computer-systems-network-security-applications-development-option-2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 05:10:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Networking & Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7718</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES Computer SystemsNetwork Security Applications Development Option Discover Advanced Elements of Network Security Development Through Various Protocols &#38; Applications The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth and depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer professionals, assisting them in widening their job opportunities [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES<br />
Computer SystemsNetwork Security Applications Development Option</p>
<p>Discover Advanced Elements of Network Security Development Through Various Protocols &amp; Applications</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth and depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer professionals, assisting them in widening their job opportunities or advancing along their career paths. Graduates are awarded a credential that is highly valued by the industry.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology degree in Computer Systems has two components. The first component is made up 42.0 credits of technical courses and major projects. This includes core courses, specialty courses (depth in a specific area) and technical electives (breadth in additional areas). The major projects allow the student to apply specialty knowledge in a real-life project, study, or applied research project. The second component consists 18.0 credits of General Education and Management courses.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is offered in a flexible delivery format to serve the needs of working professionals. Candidates can take course loads ranging from a minimum of three courses per year to an equivalent of a full-time program of studies. Most courses are offered in the evening or on weekends. Some are offered online through Web-based courses or during the day (depending on demand). Applicants can apply to the program at any time through the year.</p>
<p>The Network Security Applications Development Option is designed to prepare graduates to design, develop and deploy advanced network applications using a variety of programming languages such as C, C++, Java, Ruby, and Python, on the Linux and Windows platforms. Graduates will understand the role of security applications, both as exploit and penetration testing tools in networks. Courses are designed to provide in-depth skills using the Berkeley socket API, and the design of implementation of advanced IPv4/IPv6 Client/Server applications. Also covered are advanced topics, such as Wireless Data Communication, and Cryptology.</p>
<p>Issues such as modularity and efficiency in the implementation of protocols are covered. The emphasis will be very much the design and implementation of high-performance, robust, and scalable network applications. Security and private data transmission techniques over public networks are covered. Client-Server applications are designed and implemented using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) API. An in-depth coverage of techniques used to design and develop secure code and robust applications will be provided. Students will also be familiarized with the Bluetooth software development techniques.</p>
<p>Advanced courses&#8217; focus will be on the research and advanced implementation of security tools such as Covert Channels, Stealth Backdoors, Trojans, Packet crafting and sniffing, and in security tools proof-of-concept and prototyping. The use of advanced raw socket and kernel-level programming techniques to implement security applications will be covered in a practical, hands-on manner.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is also offered in a full-time format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/computer-systems-network-security-applications-development-option-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Systems (Network Security Applications Development Option)</title>
		<link>/computer-systems-network-security-applications-development-option/</link>
		<comments>/computer-systems-network-security-applications-development-option/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 05:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Networking & Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7716</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES Computer SystemsNetwork Security Applications Development Option Discover Advanced Elements of Network Security Development Through Various Protocols &#38; Applications The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth and depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer professionals, assisting them in widening their job opportunities [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES<br />
Computer SystemsNetwork Security Applications Development Option</p>
<p>Discover Advanced Elements of Network Security Development Through Various Protocols &amp; Applications</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth and depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer professionals, assisting them in widening their job opportunities or advancing along their career paths. Graduates are awarded a credential that is highly valued by the industry.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology degree in Computer Systems has two components. The first component is made up 42.0 credits of technical courses and major projects. This includes core courses, specialty courses (depth in a specific area) and technical electives (breadth in additional areas). The major projects allow the student to apply specialty knowledge in a real-life project, study, or applied research project. The second component consists 18.0 credits of General Education and Management courses.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is offered in a flexible delivery format to serve the needs of working professionals. Candidates can take course loads ranging from a minimum of three courses per year to an equivalent of a full-time program of studies. Most courses are offered in the evening or on weekends. Some are offered online through Web-based courses or during the day (depending on demand). Applicants can apply to the program at any time through the year.</p>
<p>The Network Security Applications Development Option is designed to prepare graduates to design, develop and deploy advanced network applications using a variety of programming languages such as C, C++, Java, Ruby, and Python, on the Linux and Windows platforms. Graduates will understand the role of security applications, both as exploit and penetration testing tools in networks. Courses are designed to provide in-depth skills using the Berkeley socket API, and the design of implementation of advanced IPv4/IPv6 Client/Server applications. Also covered are advanced topics, such as Wireless Data Communication, and Cryptology.</p>
<p>Issues such as modularity and efficiency in the implementation of protocols are covered. The emphasis will be very much the design and implementation of high-performance, robust, and scalable network applications. Security and private data transmission techniques over public networks are covered. Client-Server applications are designed and implemented using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) API. An in-depth coverage of techniques used to design and develop secure code and robust applications will be provided. Students will also be familiarized with the Bluetooth software development techniques.</p>
<p>Advanced courses&#8217; focus will be on the research and advanced implementation of security tools such as Covert Channels, Stealth Backdoors, Trojans, Packet crafting and sniffing, and in security tools proof-of-concept and prototyping. The use of advanced raw socket and kernel-level programming techniques to implement security applications will be covered in a practical, hands-on manner.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is also offered in a full-time format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/computer-systems-network-security-applications-development-option/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Computer Systems (Wireless and Mobile Applications Development Option)</title>
		<link>/computer-systems-wireless-and-mobile-applications-development-option/</link>
		<comments>/computer-systems-wireless-and-mobile-applications-development-option/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 04:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[PR]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Computing & IT]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Courses]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Networking & Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Software Development]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://washingtonstateit.org/?p=7714</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES Computer SystemsWireless and Mobile Applications Development Option More Than Developing and Deploying Wireless Applications on Cell Phones and PDAs Note: New admission procedures effective November 15, 2013. Review the instructions carefully. View summary of the changes The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>SCHOOL OF COMPUTING AND ACADEMIC STUDIES<br />
Computer SystemsWireless and Mobile Applications Development Option</p>
<p>More Than Developing and Deploying Wireless Applications on Cell Phones and PDAs</p>
<p>Note: New admission procedures effective November 15, 2013. Review the instructions carefully. View summary of the changes</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems degree is designed to increase the breadth and depth of knowledge and practical skills of computer professionals, assisting them in widening their job opportunities or advancing along their career paths. Graduates are awarded a credential that is highly valued by industry.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology degree in Computer Systems has two components. The first component is made up 42.0 credits of technical courses and major projects. This includes core courses, specialty courses (depth in a specific area) and technical electives (breadth in additional areas). The major projects allow the student to apply specialty knowledge in a real-life project, study, or applied research project. The second component consists 18.0 credits of General Education and Management courses.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is offered in a flexible delivery format to serve the needs of working professionals. Candidates can take course loads ranging from a minimum of three courses per year to an equivalent of a full-time program of studies. Most courses are offered in the evening or on weekends. Some are offered online through Web-based courses or during the day (depending on demand). Applicants can apply to the program at any time through the year.</p>
<p>The Bachelor of Technology in Computer Systems is also offered in a full-time format.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>/computer-systems-wireless-and-mobile-applications-development-option/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
